academics.com 2017-02-25

# Privacy Policy - academics

academics GmbH   
Speersort 1   
D-20095 Hamburg   
Tel: 040-320 273-3   
Mail: [contact@academics.com](mailto:contact@academics.com)

We assure you that your data will be used in accordance with the pertinent data protection regulations, the German Teleservices Act, Interstate Broadcasting Agreement, German Data Protection Act and other data protection provisions. Your personal data will only be saved in a machine-readable format, processed and used for the purpose for which you have given it. The only exceptions to this shall be if you have agreed to a different use. We would like to inform you hereinafter in what way and for what purpose your data will be used. 

The data that we collect comprises: 

****(a) personal data**** , which you enter voluntarily when registering for our newsletter, place an order, complete a survey, participate in our discussion forums, enter a competition or make use of similar services.   
****(b) Tracking information**** , which is transmitted when you use our services. 

## (a) Personal Data

We are entitled to collect, process, save and use your personal data when you use a service insofar as it is necessary to enable you to make use of the service. We ensure that your data is treated as confidential. 

Subsequent to your voluntary consent, we are entitled to collect, process and save personal data, to merge it with other data, archive it and use it. Subsequent to your consent, we are entitled to pass on personal data to third parties for the purpose of advertising, market research and other commercial services. Insofar as you have consented to the use of personal data for specific purposes that are subject to the requirement of consent, you can revoke this consent at any time. The data will then be deleted at our company. Insofar as data has been transmitted to third parties with your consent, these third parties will be informed directly and requested to delete the data. You are entitled to restrict the consent to the use of your data. The data will then only be deleted in line with the restriction. 

Without your consent we shall be permitted to pass on your data in the following cases: 

  * as and when we involve other companies to support us in fulfilling the contract, e.g. in order to process purchase orders, process billing, to render customer services, despatch goods or carry out other functions necessary for performing the service 
  * if we are obliged to pass on personal data by law or by a court we will inform you - if permissible - without delay of the transmission of the data. 

You are entitled to view, correct or delete the personal data you have given us at any time. If this is not technically possible at the address where you entered the data, you have the option of requesting your personal data, checking it and, if applicable, deleting it via the following address: [contact@academics.com](mailto:contact@academics.com). 

## (b) Tracking Information

General, non-personal data regarding usage is collected and saved on our website. Hereinafter you will find a list of purposes and web analysis services used. 

In order to facilitate an analysis of the use of our website we use so-called "cookies", text files which are stored locally on your computer and thus facilitate recognition when you visit our website again. This technology allows us to recognise you as a visitor and enables us to offer you personalised services. In order to better understand the usage behaviour of our users, IP addresses may be stored in encrypted form. The encryption is carried out using an md5 hash function, which rules out the possibility of reproducing the IP addresses at a later date or identifying users. Your personal data therefore remains anonymised using this function. 

This information is collected without your express consent. You can however opt out at any time with effect for the future. To do this you simply have to accept a relevant cookie. This cookie contains no information about you and cannot be assigned to a specific person in principle. As soon as the track servers read this cookie the saving of your visitor data is blocked. As long as you do not delete this cookie on your computer no data is saved. However, this only applies to the computer and the browser where the cookie was filed. 

We use the following tools on our website: 

## 1.) Webtrekk

We make use of the services from the company Webtrekk GmbH, Hannoversche Strasse 19, 10115 Berlin (hereinafter referred to as "Webtrekk") in order to collect statistical data regarding the use of our website, to constantly improve and optimise it and thus make it more interesting for you. Some of the data collected during your visit to this website is used for statistical analysis. A direct reference to a person is ruled out at all times. The data collected in this way serves to establish anonymous user profiles, which form the basis for web statistics. The data collected using the Webtrekk technology is not used to personally identify the visitors to this website and is not merged with personal data relating to the bearer of the pseudonym at any time. The data is only transmitted to Webtrekk, who processes it exclusively for a specific purpose and contract. Webtrekk is certified in the data protection field by TÜV Saarland. 

When you visit our website, information transmitted by your browser is collected and analysed. It is collected using pixel technology and so-called cookies, which are integrated into every website. The cookies serve to recognise new and regular visitors and are limited to a maximum storage of six months for statistical analysis on the advice of the data protection authorities. 

The following data is collected: 

  * Request (file name of the requested file)
  * Browser type/version 
  * Browser language 
  * Operating system used 
  * Internal resolution of the browser window 
  * Screen resolution
  * Java script activation
  * Java on / off
  * Cookies on / off
  * Colour intensity
  * Referrer URL 
  * IP address - is immediately anonymised and deleted again after processing 
  * Time of access 
  * Clicks
  * If applicable, content of forms (in the case of free text fields, only "completed" or "not completed" is transferred)

The IP address is transmitted every time a server request is made so that the server knows where the reply has to be sent. Everyone receives an IP address from an Internet service provider (ISP) as soon as they connect to the Internet and the ISP can always trace which IP address was allocated to which of its customers at what time. As long as the IP address is stored, the identity of the Internet subscriber can theoretically be discovered via the circuitous route of the ISP. 

Our statistics service provider therefore only saves the IP address in abbreviated (anonymised) form and only uses it for session recognition, geo localisation (down to town/city level) and for averting attacks. The IP address is then deleted again immediately so that the collected data is anonymous and an attribution to the identity of the user is no longer possible even via the circuitous route of the ISP. 

As a website visitor you can opt out of your anonymised visitor data being saved so that it is no longer collected (acquired) in future. A cookie called "webtrekkOptOut" is set for the exclusion of Webtrekk web controlling. This cookie is valid for 12 months. Your opt-out is valid for as long as you do not delete the cookie. Please note that if you delete all cookies on your computer this opt-out cookie will also be deleted, i.e. if you wish to continue opting out of anonymised data collection by Webtrekk you will have to set this opt-out cookie again. The cookie is set for the given domain per browser and computer. If you visit our website at home and at work or using various browsers you will have to activate the opt-out cookie in the various browsers and on the various computers. 

In order to complete the opt-out please click on the following link: [opt out of tracking ](https://www.webtrekk.com/de/index/opt-out-webtrekk/abmeldung-vom-tracking/)

## 2.) Google Analytics

In order to improve and develop our website and services, we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service. These are services provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google uses so-called "cookies", text files which are stored on your computer and facilitate analysis of your use of the website. The information regarding your use of this website (including your IP address) generated by the cookie is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. 

IP anonymisation is active on this website. Your IP address is abbreviated beforehand by Google inside member states of the European Union or other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address transmitted to a Google server in the USA and abbreviated there. 

Google will only use this information to analyse your use of the website, compile reports on website activities for the website operators and render other services connected with website use and internet use. Google will also transmit this information to third parties, if necessary, insofar as this is stipulated by law or insofar as third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Third party providers, including Google, place advertisements on websites on the Internet. They use stored cookies to place advertisements on the basis of previous visits to this website by a user. 

Google will not link your IP address to other data. You can prevent the storage of cookies by changing the settings on your browser software accordingly; we would point out, however, that if you do this you may not be able to use all of the functions on this website fully. Moreover, you can prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) by Google and the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link: [Browser add-on for the deactivation of Google Analytics](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de)

You can obtain further information on deactivation from the [page regarding deactivating Google advertising](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) or on the [deactivation page of the network advertising organisation](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). 

You can opt out of the collection and storage of data at any time with effect for the future. You can find additional information regarding Google's policies [here](http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/). 

## 3.) Google Adwords / Google Tag Manager / Google Dynamic Remarketing

Our website uses Google AdWords and Google Tag Manager for the purpose of personalised, interest and location-related online advertising. 

These services enable us to address visitors to our website within the scope of marketing campaigns regarding our products on the websites of our advertising partners using targeted advertising. This form of advertising is carried out anonymously. The advertising material on the websites of our partners is displayed by means of Google AdWords, Google dynamic remarketing and Google Tag Manager on the basis of cookie technology ("DoubleClick cookies") and the previous visit to our website. The data is collected and stored by Google. Our advertising partners do not receive any information about the data stored in the cookie. 

As well as the IP address of the computer being used, an ID number is stored in the cookie with which Google can determine how often you have called up which website. No other personal data such as email address, company name or telephone numbers is stored apart from the IP address. The data stored in the cookie is not merged with other personal data to produce user profiles. Users can deactivate DoubleClick remarketing pixel by calling up the [deactivation page for Google advertising](http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/technologies/ads/) or the [deactivation page of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). 

## 4.) Facebook

Plug-ins from the social network www.facebook.com by Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, are integrated into our website. The Facebook plug-ins recognise you when you use the Facebook logo or a Facebook button (e.g. the "Like" button) on our website. If you click on the Facebook "Like" button you can show that you like the website or certain content and link these contents to your Facebook profile. By doing this, information is transferred directly to Facebook by your browser and stored there. If you are logged in on Facebook, Facebook can directly attribute your retrieval of our website to your Facebook account. Even if you are not logged in or do not have a Facebook account at all, your browser transmits information (e.g. which website you have called up and your IP address), which is stored by Facebook. Please visit Facebook's privacy policy for details of how your personal data is handled by Facebook and your rights in this respect: [Facebook privacy policy](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php). 

If you do not want Facebook to attribute the data collected about you via our website to your Facebook account, you must log out of your Facebook user account before you visit our website. 

## 5.) Twitter

We use social plug-in functions from Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. 

By using Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" function the websites you visit are linked to your Twitter account and disclosed to other users. Data is also transferred to Twitter in the process. You can find details on how Twitter handles your data and your rights and setting options to protect your personal data in [Twitter's privacy policy](http://twitter.com/privacy). 

## 6.) Use of Google +

Our website uses the "+1-Button" from the social network Google Plus, operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google"). 

The button is recognisable from the "+1" logo on a white or coloured background. By clicking the button you can publish information worldwide as a Google Plus user. 

If you call up a website which contains such a button, your browser already establishes a direct connection to Google servers. The content of the "+1" button is transmitted directly to your browser by Google and integrated into the website by it. We therefore have no influence on the scope of data that Google collects with this button. According to Google, no personal data is collected unless you click on the button. Such data, including the IP address, is only collected and processed in the case of members who are logged in. 

Please see the [Google privacy policy regarding the "+1" interface](http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html) and the [FAQ](http://support.google.com/plus/bin/answer.py?hl=de&answer=1319578&rd=1) regarding the purpose and scope of data collection and further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and setting options in this respect to protect your personal life. 

If you are a member of Google Plus and do not wish Google to collect data about you via our website and link it to your member data stored by Google, it is sufficient for you to log out of your Google Plus user account before you visit our website. 

## 7.) INFOnline

Our website uses the "scalable centralised measurement system" (SZM) from [INFOnline](https://www.infonline.de/) for determining statistical parameters regarding the use of our website. 

Anonymous measured values are collected in the process. The SZM audience measurement system either uses a cookie with the identifier "ivwbox.de" or alternatively a signature, which is compiled from various pieces of automatically transferred information about your computer, to recognise computer systems. IP addresses are not stored in the system and are only processed in anonymised form. The audience measurement system was developed in compliance with data protection. The aim of audience measurement is to statistically determine usage intensity and the number of users of a website. At no point in time are individual users identified. Your identity always remains protected. You will not receive any advertising via the system. 

For websites which are members of the Informationsgemeinschaft zur Feststellung der Verbreitung von Werbeträgern e.V. (IVW - www.ivw.eu) or participate in the "internet facts" study by the Arbeitsgemeinschaft Online-Forschung e.V. (AGOF - www.agof.de), the user statistics are published monthly by the AGOF and the Arbeitsgemeinschaft Media-Analyse e.V. (ag.ma - www.agma-mmc.de), as well as by the IVW and can be viewed at www.agof.de, www.agma-mmc.de and www.ivw.eu. 

As well as publication of measurement data, the IVW also reviews the SZM system regularly with respect to usage conforming to the rules and to data protection. You can find more information about the SZM system on the [INFOnline GmbH](https://www.infonline.de/) website, which operates the SZM system, the data protection site of [AGOF](http://www.agof.de/datenschutz) and the data protection site of [IVW](http://www.ivw.eu/). You can opt out of data processing by SZM [here](http://optout.ivwbox.de/). 

## 8.) Xing

This website uses the "share button" from XING. Therefore when you call up this website a connection is established by your browser to the servers of XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. The share functions (e.g. the display of the counter value) are thereby performed. Your personal data is not saved in the process by calling up this website. In particular, no IP addresses are saved by XING. Likewise, your usage behaviour is not analysed. You can read up-to-date information regarding data protection in relation to the "share" button and other relevant information [here](https://www.xing.com/app/share?op=data_protection). 

## 9.) Wordpress Stats

This website uses Wordpress Stats, a tool for the statistical analysis of visitor access, operated by [Automattic](http://automattic.com/) Inc., 60 29th Street #343, San Francisco, CA 94110-4929, USA, using tracking technology from [Quantcast](https://www.quantcast.com/) Inc., 201 3rd St, Floor 2, San Francisco, CA 94103-3153, USA. 

WordPress.com-Stats uses so-called "cookies", text files which are stored on your computer and facilitate analysis of your use of the website. The information regarding your use of this website generated by the cookie is saved on a server in the USA. The IP address is anonymised immediately after processing and before it is saved. You can prevent the installation of the cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; we would point out, however, that if you do this you may not be able to use all of the functions on this website fully. You can opt out of the collection and use of the data by Quantcast with effect for the future by clicking on the link "Click here to opt-out" and [setting an opt-out cookie in your browser](http://www.quantcast.com/opt-out). If you delete all cookies on your computer you will have to reset the opt-out cookie. 

## 10.) ADITION

Data is collected and saved on this website for marketing and optimisation purposes using the ADITION adserving technology from ADITION technologies AG. Pseudonymised user profiles can be created from this data. Cookies may be used for this purpose. The data collected using the ADITION adserving technology is not used to personally identify the visitors to this website and is not merged with personal data regarding the bearer of the pseudonym. ADITION technologies AG does not save any personal data by setting cookies. The information only contains technical information such as the browser used or the operating system installed. You can opt out of the collection and storage of data at any time with effect for the future. You can [use this link](http://www.adition.com/kontakt/datenschutz/) to do this. 

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy we would be happy to help. You can contact us at: 

academics GmbH   
Speersort 1   
D-20095 Hamburg   
Tel: 040-320 273-3   
Mail: [contact@academics.com](mailto:contact@academics.com)
